Jeff Shi

jeff.shi@utexas.edu /jbshi jeffshi.github.io

(214)-235-9679

OPERATIONS RESEARCH ANALYST Captain, USAF

SUMMARY

Operations Research Analyst with 5 years of experience in Business Intelligence and Project Management. Experienced in Big Data analytics, R and Python programming, and providing data-based insights that enable informed, strategic decision-making. Separating from military service and relocating back to Plano, TX (hometown). Seeking to transition into a Business Intelligence or Data Science career.

PROGRAMMING & SOFTWARE SKILLS

Proficient: Java, R, VBA Analytic Tools: Excel, Minitab, Stat-Ease Experienced: Python, SQL, Hadoop Software: WEKA, Eclipse, RStudio Exposed to: C/C++ OS: Windows, Linux

EXPERIENCE

Chief of Assessments (Senior Business Intelligence Analyst) | Tucson, AZ

12th Air Force (Air Forces Southern) | 2014 - Present

- Authors and delivers data-driven insights of corporate strategy to the Commander (3-Star General).
- Quantitatively assesses planning and execution of major military operations in South America.
- Designs methods to analyze the impact of operations, resulting in changes to business strategy.
- Wrote R scripts that optimized data analysis during military exercises, saving 20 man-hours.

Chief, Security Trends (Senior Data Analyst) | Camp Arifjan, Kuwait

Combined Joint Task Force – Operation Inherent Resolve (CJTF-OIR) | Nov 2015 – May 2016

- ▶ Drove informed decision-making by regularly briefing executive-level leadership on security trends that affect the campaign to defeat the Islamic State (ISIS).
- ▶ Led cross-team efforts to improve the security picture for Northern Iraq by 50%, solving critical intelligence deficiencies affecting 6 stakeholder groups.
- ▶ Utilized SQL to guery large data sets and gather relevant information to conduct trend analysis.
- ▶ Saved 60-man hours per month by using R and VBA to automate collection, cleaning, and analysis of large structured and unstructured data (>1M data points).

Project Manager, Test Operations | Las Vegas, NV

59th Test and Evaluation Squadron | 2013 - 2014

- Led analysis team in planning, executing, and analyzing five test programs, fielding \$80 million in new medical evacuation technology and search and rescue tactics.
- Managed land rescue test program to address Africa mission requirements, resulting in the procurement of 60 next-generation vehicles and satisfying Special Operations stakeholder needs.

Senior Operations Research Analyst | Las Vegas, NV

59th Test and Evaluation Squadron | 2012 - 2013

- ▶ Led Test and Evaluation analysis for prototype upgrades for the HH-6oG helicopter.
- Applied Design of Experiments to shape test trials for five projects valued at \$60 million.
- ▶ Used Excel to analyze and visualize data and drive fielding decisions for experimental products.
- Authored technical reports that informed technical and non-technical stakeholders of test results, enabling data-based acquisition decisions that delivered reliable equipment to warfighters.

EDUCATION

Georgia Institute of Technology / Class of 2018

MS Student | Computer Science (Machine Learning Focus)

New Mexico State University / 2013

MS | Industrial Engineering

University of Texas / 2011

BS | Computer Science